Barry Commoner Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Organizations File, 1919-1980 (Box 321-441)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS), 1919-1975 (Box 321-379)
    - Committee on Environmental Alterations (Box 332)
      - American Friends Service Committee, 1972 (Box 333)
      - Asia, 1967-1972, (2 folders) (Box 333)
      - Bibliographies, 1971-1973, (3 folders) (Box 334)
      - Black Mesa Defense Fund, 1971 (Box 334)
      - "Blueprint for Survival, A", 1972 (Box 334)
      - California, 1967-1971 (Box 334)
      - Charcoal, 1919, 1969 (Box 334)
      - Copper, 1972 (Box 334)
      - Correspondence, 1969-1973, (2 folders) (Box 334)
      - Correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 335)
      - Cotton, 1968-1973, (2 folders) (Box 335)
      - Detergents, 1967-1970 (Box 335)
      - Economic growth, 1968-1973, (3 folders) (Box 335)
      - Economic growth, 1968-1973, (4 folders) (Box 336)
      - Electric power study group (Box 336)
        - Abstracts, 1971 (Box 336)
        - Budgets, 1970-1973, (2 folders) (Box 336)
        - Clippings, 1971-1973 (Box 337)
        - Correspondence, 1970-1974, (5 folders) (Box 337)
        - Final report, 1972, (2 folders) (Box 338)
        - Fossil fuels, 1967-1972, (2 folders) (Box 338)
        - General, 1970-1974, (6 folders) (Box 339)
        - General, 1970-1974, (2 folders) (Box 340)
        - Grant proposals, 1970-1972, (2 folders) (Box 340)
        - Graphs, 1969-1972, (2 folders) (Box 340)
        - Graphs, 1969-1972 (Box 341)
        - Household appliances, 1967-1973, (2 folders) (Box 341)
        - Interim progress report, 1970-1971 (Box 341)
        - Meetings, 1970-1971 (Box 341)
        - Outlines, 1970-1972, (2 folders) (Box 341)
        - Report drafts, 1971-1973, (7 folders) (Box 342)
        - Report drafts, 1971-1973, (6 folders) (Box 343)
        - Report drafts, 1971-1973, (6 folders) (Box 344)
        - Report drafts, 1971-1973, (7 folders) (Box 345)
        - Report drafts, 1971-1973, (6 folders) (Box 346)
        - Report drafts, 1971-1973, (6 folders) (Box 347)
        - Report drafts, 1971-1973 (Box 348)
        - Seattle City Light, 1967-1972, (3 folders) (Box 348)
      - Energy consumption, 1941-1973, (3 folders) (Box 348)
      - Energy consumption, 1941-1973, (3 folders) (Box 349)
      - Energy crisis symposium, Philadelphia, Pa., 1970-1972, (3 folders) (Box 349)
      - Energy crisis symposium, Philadelphia, Pa., 1970-1972, (6 folders) (Box 350)
      - Expenses, 1969-1973, (2 folders) (Box 351)
      - Food production, 1960-1971 (Box 351)
      - Forestry, 1951-1973, (4 folders) (Box 351)
      - Forestry, 1951-1973, (6 folders) (Box 352)
      - Forestry, 1951-1973, (2 folders) (Box 353)
      - Funding, 1972-1973 (Box 353)
      - Garvey, Gerald, 1971-1972 (Box 353)
      - General, 1968-1973, (3 folders) (Box 353)
      - General, 1968-1973, (4 folders) (Box 354)
      - Geothermal energy, 1968-1972, (2 folders) (Box 354)
      - Herbicides, 1970-1973 (Box 355)
      - Likens, Gene, 1967-1970, (2 folders) (Box 355)
      - Meetings, 1968-1973, (3 folders) (Box 355)
      - Meetings, 1968-1973, (4 folders) (Box 356)
      - Membership, 1972-1973 (Box 356)
      - Memoranda, 1970-1973 (Box 356)
      - Mercury, 1970-1971 (Box 357)
      - Nitrogen, 1962-1971, (2 folders) (Box 357)
      - Nuclear power plants, 1968-1971, (3 folders) (Box 357)
      - Overpopulation, 1958-1971, (6 folders) (Box 358)
      - Overpopulation, 1958-1971, (3 folders) (Box 359)
      - Personnel, 1970-1973 (Box 359)
      - Pesticides, 1970-1971 (Box 359)
      - Plastics, 1968-1971 (Box 359)
      - Pollution, 1961-1971 (Box 359)
      - Pulp and paper industry, 1971-1972 (Box 359)
      - Quinault tribe, 1970-1972 (Box 360)
      - Rubber, 1969-1972 (Box 360)
      - Sewage recycling, 1968-1970 (Box 360)
      - Solid waste, 1969-1972, (2 folders) (Box 360)
      - Stamler, Paul, 1972 (Box 360)
      - Sulfur oxides, 1970-1973 (Box 360)
      - Transportation, 1962-1972 (Box 360)
      - Transportation, 1962-1972, (3 folders) (Box 361)
      - United States Senate, 1970-1973 (Box 361)
      - Work injuries, 1970-1972 (Box 361)
    - Committee on Governance, 1967-1971 (Box 361)
    - Committee on Humanistic Implication of Science and Technology, 1970 (Box 361)
    - Committee on Industry, Technology, and Society, 1973-1974 (Box 362)
    - Committee on Minorities in Science, 1971-1972 (Box 362)
    - Committee on Nominations, 1956 (Box 362)
    - Committee on Population and Reproduction Control, 1969-1971 (Box 362)
    - Committee on the Public Understanding of Science, 1967-1973 (Box 362)
    - Committee on Science in the Promotion of Human Welfare (Box 362)
      - Birth control symposium, Berkeley, Calif., 1965-1969 (Box 362)
      - Civil defense symposium, Berkeley, Calif., 1965-1966, (2 folders) (Box 362)
      - Correspondence (Box 362)
        - 1959 (Box 362)
        - 1960-1961, (6 folders) (Box 363)
        - 1961-1967, (8 folders) (Box 364)
      - "Ethics and the Social Relations of Science," 1961-1965, (3 folders) (Box 365)
      - General, 1957-1974, (4 folders) (Box 365)
      - "The Integrity of Science," 1963-1967, (6 folders) (Box 366)
      - "The Integrity of Science," 1963-1967, (6 folders) (Box 367)
      - Meetings, 1963-1967 (Box 368)
      - Rapaport, Anatol, 1965-1966 (Box 368)
      - "Science and Drug Hazards," 1964 (Box 368)
      - "Science and Human Survival," 1960-1961, (4 folders) (Box 368)
      - Sonic booms, 1961-1965 (Box 368)
      - "Values and Uses of Science," 1968-1969 (Box 368)
    - Committee on Science and Public Policy, 1973-1975 (Box 369)
    - Committee on the Social Aspects of Science, 1956-1959, (6 folders) (Box 369)
    - Committee on the Social Aspects of Science, 1956-1959, (6 folders) (Box 370)
    - Committee on Young Scientists, 1970 (Box 370)
    - Correspondence (Box 371)
      - 1953-1964, (8 folders) (Box 371)
      - 1965-1973, (9 folders) (Box 372)
      - 1974, (3 folders) (Box 373)
    - Executive Committee, 1968-1974 (Box 373)
    - General, 1958-1974, (2 folders) (Box 373)
    - General, 1958-1974, (2 folders) (Box 374)
    - Grants, 1952-1959, (4 folders) (Box 374)
    - International development conference, Philadelphia, Pa., 1971-1972 (Box 374)
    - International development conference, Philadelphia, Pa., 1971-1972, (6 folders) (Box 375)
    - International development conference, Philadelphia, Pa., 1971-1972 (Box 376)
    - Miscellany, 1971-1972 (Box 376)
    - Newcomb Cleveland Prize Committee, 1964-1969, (4 folders) (Box 376)
    - Office on Opportunities in Science, 1972-1974 (Box 376)
    - Parliament of Science, 1958 (Box 377)
    - Popular book program, 1955-1961, (2 folders) (Box 377)
    - Publications, 1962-1973, (3 folders) (Box 377)
    - Publications, 1962-1973, (2 folders) (Box 378)
    - Section secretaries, 1971-1973 (Box 378)
    - Segregation, 1955-1956 (Box 378)
    - Symposium on Ethics of Science, Montreal, Canada, 1964, (3 folders) (Box 88)
    - Symposium on Secrecy, Privacy, and Public Information, New York, N.Y., 1967-1971 (Box 378)
    - Technology assessment, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 378)
    - Television broadcasts, 1968-1972 (Box 378)
    - Unidentified flying objects, 1969 (Box 378)
    - Youth Council, 1969-1972, (2 folders) (Box 379)
  - Center for the Biology of Natural Systems (CBNS), 1951-1980 (Box 379-397)
    Commoner was the founder and director of the Center for the Biology of Natural Systems (CBNS), an environmental health sciences research center created in 1966 and based at Washington University, where Commoner was a faculty member. CBNS moved to Queens College, City University of New York in 1981. Queens College changed its name to the Barry Commoner Center for Health and the Environment in 2015. More files pertaining to CBNS are in both the 1990 and 2019 Additions.
    Material types include correspondence, committee and task force records, grant and financial material, research reports, and speeches and writings.
    Arranged alphabetically by topic material type.
    - Air Pollution Task Force, 1969-1973, (2 folders) (Box 379)
    - Bibliography, 1974-1979 (Box 379)
    - Budgets, 1970-1973 (Box 379)
    - Clippings, 1965-1977 (Box 379)
    - Correspondence (Box 379)
      - 1965, (2 folders) (Box 379)
      - 1966-1972, (7 folders) (Box 380)
      - 1972-1978, (5 folders) (Box 381)
    - Events, 1966-1976, (2 folders) (Box 381)
    - Executive Committee, 1968-1972 (Box 381)
    - Farvar, Taghi, 1970-1973 (Box 382)
    - Fellows, 1965-1971, (4 folders) (Box 382)
    - Foundations, 1963-1973, (2 folders) (Box 382)
    - General (Box 383)
      - 1968-1975, (7 folders) (Box 383)
      - 1975 (Box 384)
    - Grants, 1951-1973 (Box 384)
    - Heavy Metals Task Force, 1971-1972 (Box 384)
    - Illinois Institute for Environmental Quality, 1972 (Box 384)
    - Illinois Pollution Control Board, 1971-1973, (3 folders) (Box 384)
    - International Task Force, 1969-1971 (Box 385)
    - Iran, 1973-1974 (Box 385)
    - Mercury Contamination Task Force, 1970-1971 (Box 385)
    - Minnesota Pollution Control Agency, 1968 (Box 385)
    - Minutes, 1964-1973, (2 folders) (Box 385)
    - National Institutes of Health, 1958-1971, (3 folders) (Box 386)
    - National Science Foundation, 1963-1972, (4 folders) (Box 386)
    - National Science Foundation, 1963-1972, (3 folders) (Box 387)
    - Nitrogen Task Force, 1970-1973, (3 folders) (Box 387)
    - Personnel, 1966-1971 (Box 387)
    - Photographs, 1967-1972 (Box 388)
    - Planning Committee, 1969-1971 (Box 388)
    - Program of Environmental Education for Students from Developing Countries, 1971-1977, (5 folders) (Box 388)
    - Program of Environmental Education for Students from Developing Countries, 1971-1977, (2 folders) (Box 389)
    - Progress reports (Box 389)
      - 1966-1968, (4 folders) (Box 389)
      - 1966-1974, (7 folders) (Box 390)
      - 1980 (Box 391)
    - Publications, 1965-1977, (3 folders) (Box 391)
    - Purpose statements, 1968-1970 (Box 391)
    - Purpose statements, 1968-1970, (2 folders) (Box 392)
    - Reference Center on Ecology and International Development, 1971-1975, (2 folders) (Box 392)
    - Research proposals (Box 392)
      - 1965-1973, (4 folders) (Box 392)
      - 1970-1973, (2 folders) (Box 393)
    - Sangamon watershed farm survey, 1973-1974 (Box 393)
    - Soil and Aquatic Task Force, 1969-1970 (Box 393)
    - Space needs, 1971-1978, (2 folders) (Box 393)
    - Speeches and writings (Box 393)
      - 1966-1969, (2 folders) (Box 393)
      - 1970-1972, (7 folders) (Box 394)
      - 1973-1976, (7 folders) (Box 395)
      - 1976-1978, (7 folders) (Box 396)
      - 1979-1980, (2 folders) (Box 397)
    - Urban Task Force, 1969-1971 (Box 397)
  - Committee for Environmental Information (CEI), 1959-1974 (Box 397-402)
    After the passage of the Nuclear Test Ban Treaty in 1963, the Committee for Nuclear Information expanded its mission to include other environmental policy issues and changed its name to the Committee for Environmental Information. Commoner continued in a leadership position. The file includes material on nuclear testing and the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, and their publications C.E. Eye, Environment, and Scientist and Citizen.
    Material types include correspondence, committee and board of directors records, financial records, and printed matter.
    Arranged alphabetically by topic or material type.
    - Board of Directors, 1967-1974, (3 folders) (Box 397)
    - Budgets, 1967-1972 (Box 397)
    - Clippings, 1968-1971 (Box 397)
    - Committees, 1964-1973, (2 folders) (Box 397)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1974, (4 folders) (Box 398)
    - Dugway Proving Ground, 1968-1969 (Box 398)
    - Fundraising, 1968-1972, (2 folders) (Box 398)
    - Nuclear testing, 1959-1969 (Box 398)
    - Nuclear testing, 1959-1969, (6 folders) (Box 399)
    - Publications (Box 399)
      - C.E. Eye, 1972-1973 (Box 399)
      - Environment, 1969-1974 (Box 399)
      - Environment, 1969-1974, (7 folders) (Box 400)
      - Scientist and Citizen, 1966-1968, (6 folders) (Box 401)
      - Scientist and Citizen, 1966-1968 (Box 402)
    - Purpose statements, 1967-1970 (Box 402)
    - Research proposals, 1968-1971 (Box 402)
    - Scientific division, 1967-1971, (2 folders) (Box 402)
  - Greater St. Louis Citizens' Committee for Nuclear Information (CNI), 1958-1968 (Box 402-406)
    Organized in 1958 by a group of scientists, including Commoner, and concerned citizens in St. Louis, Missouri, who believed the public should have accurate information about nuclear energy and radioactive fallout from nuclear weapons testing. Material from the Baby Tooth Survey and the biological effects of radioactive fallout is included here. The organization was one of many committees around the country whose shared name was the Committee for Nuclear Information (CNI). More files pertaining to this organization and the publication Nuclear Information are in the 2019 Addition.
    Material types include correspondence, financial records, grant proposals, minutes of meetings, press releases, printed material, and testimonies.
    - Baby tooth survey, 1958-1968, undated, (3 folders) (Box 402)
    - Civil defense, 1960-1962, undated (Box 402)
    - Correspondence (Box 403)
      - 1958-1962, (8 folders) (Box 403)
      - 1963-1967, (5 folders) (Box 404)
    - Draft paper, 1966-1967 (Box 404)
    - Financial records, 1966-1967 (Box 404)
    - General, circa 1958-circa 1963, (2 folders) (Box 404)
    - General, circa 1958-circa 1963, (4 folders) (Box 405)
    - Grant proposals, circa 1963-1966, (3 folders) (Box 405)
    - Leitenberg, Milton, 1966-1967 (Box 405)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1959-1967 (Box 406)
    - Newspaper clippings, pamphlets, and other printed matter, 1958-1964 (Box 406)
    - Nuclear Information, 1958-1964 (Box 406)
    - Other science information organizations, 1960-1963, undated, (2 folders) (Box 406)
    - Presidential election, 1964 (Box 406)
    - Press releases, 1959-1962 (Box 406)
    - Project Harbor, 1965-1967 (Box 406)
    - Testimonies, 1963-1966 (Box 406)
  - Scientists' Institute for Public Information (SIPI), 1963-1975 (Box 406-413)
    Founded in 1963 by Commoner and others as a coordinating body for twenty-three regional Committees for Nuclear/Environmental Information. Over time, the affiliates ceased operating and SIPI inherited the mission of delivering accurate scientific information to the public on a wide range of scientific issues affecting public policy. More files pertaining to SIPI are in the 2019 Addition.
    Material types include correspondence, newsletters, press releases, meeting agendas and minutes, and financial material.
    - Annual meetings, 1973-1974 (Box 406)
    - Bantam Lecture Bureau, 1972 (Box 407)
    - Board of Directors, 1963-1973, (3 folders) (Box 407)
    - Budget, 1963-1973 (Box 407)
    - Cayuga Lake, N.Y., 1968-1969 (Box 407)
    - Committees, 1963-1973, (2 folders) (Box 407)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1974, (6 folders) (Box 408)
    - Energy Convocation, 1973-1975, (6 folders) (Box 409)
    - Energy Convocation, 1973-1975, (6 folders) (Box 410)
    - Environmental News Service, 1972-1973 (Box 411)
    - Fellows, 1971-1973 (Box 411)
    - First Spectrum Fund, 1972-1973 (Box 411)
    - Fundraising, 1970-1973 (Box 411)
    - Grants, 1964-1974, (3 folders) (Box 411)
    - Memoranda, 1964-1971, 1966-1971; (2 folders) (Box 412)
    - Michigan Information Movement, 1968-1969 (Box 412)
    - National Association for the Environment proposal, 1970 (Box 412)
    - Newsletters, 1970-1973 (Box 412)
    - Press releases, 1963-1974 (Box 412)
    - Scientists' Inst. for Pub. Information, Inc. v. Atomic Energy Comm'n, et. al., 1972-1974 See also containers 313-316, Liquid fast breeder reactors, (2 folders) (Box 412)
    - Scientists' Inst. for Pub. Information, Inc. v. Atomic Energy Comm'n, et. al., 1972-1974, (2 folders) (Box 413)
    - Statement of purpose and bylaws, 1965-1972 (Box 413)
    - Transfer of Environment magazine, 1971-1972, (2 folders) (Box 413)
    - Workbooks, 1969-1970 (Box 413)
    - Workshop, 1968 (Box 413)
  - Washington University, St. Louis, Mo., 1948-1975 (Box 414-441)
    Items from Commoner's faculty membership at the university with a focus on the activities of the botany and other science departments.
    Material types include corrrespondence, reports, grants, financial material, course outlines and papers, and faculty and university communications.
    - Accounting, 1966-1973, (2 folders) (Box 414)
    - Admissions, 1960-1969 (Box 414)
    - Adolphus Busch III Laboratory of Biology, 1956-1959, (2 folders) (Box 414)
    - Atomic energy byproduct license, 1957-1968 (Box 414)
    - Biology Department, 1962-1978, (6 folders) (Box 415)
    - Biology Department, 1962-1978, (2 folders) (Box 416)
    - Botany Department (Box 416)
      - 1948-1969, (4 folders) (Box 416)
      - 1964-1969, (3 folders) (Box 417)
    - Budgets, 1959-1966 (Box 417)
    - Business office, 1966-1969 (Box 417)
    - Center-Botany building proposal, 1960-1971, (2 folders) (Box 417)
    - Center-Botany building proposal, 1960-1971, (6 folders) (Box 418)
    - Chancellor's office, 1966-1969 (Box 418)
    - Chemical-Biological Coordination Center, 1951-1954 (Box 419)
    - Chemistry Department, 1967 (Box 419)
    - College of Arts and Sciences (Box 419)
      - 1965-1968, (5 folders) (Box 419)
      - 1966-1969, (4 folders) (Box 420)
    - Comptroller's Office, 1966-1969 (Box 420)
    - Continuing education, 1967-1969 (Box 420)
    - Correspondence (Box 421)
      - 1948-1972, (6 folders) (Box 421)
      - 1965-1972 (Box 422)
    - Educational television, 1956 (Box 422)
    - Effort reporting, 1966-1969, (4 folders) (Box 422)
    - Executive Advisory Committee, 1953-1956 (Box 422)
    - Financial review, 1967-1968, (3 folders) (Box 423)
    - Franklin, Rosalind, 1955 (Box 423)
    - Freshman orientation, 1966-1967 (Box 423)
    - "Frontiers of Science" lecture series, 1955-1959 (Box 423)
    - Fundraising, 1955-1970, (2 folders) (Box 423)
    - Fundraising, 1955-1970 (Box 424)
    - General (Box 424)
      - 1948-1958, (5 folders) (Box 424)
      - 1959-1968, (5 folders) (Box 425)
      - 1969-1973, (7 folders) (Box 426)
      - 1972-1975, (3 folders) (Box 427)
    - General studies course, 1973 (Box 427)
    - Graduate Institute of Education, 1966 (Box 427)
    - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, 1957-1969, (3 folders) (Box 427)
    - Graduate students, 1948-1972 (Box 428)
    - Grants, 1958-1972, (4 folders) (Box 428)
    - Greenhouses (Box 428)
      - 1954-1962 (Box 428)
      - 1972 (Box 429)
    - Hazzard, George W., 1966-1970 (Box 429)
    - Jagendorf, Andre T., 1954 (Box 429)
    - Job applicants, 1952-1968, (4 folders) (Box 429)
    - Job applicants, 1952-1968 (Box 430)
    - Keys, 1975-1979 (Box 95)
    - Lab equipment, 1950-1961 (Box 430)
    - Libraries, 1963-1972, (3 folders) (Box 430)
    - Maintenance requests, 1966-1969 (Box 430)
    - Newsletters, 1974-1975 (Box 430)
    - Notes, 1951-1970 (Box 431)
    - Patent applications, 1951-1960, (2 folders) (Box 431)
    - Personnel Department, 1966-1969, (2 folders) (Box 431)
    - Press releases (Box 431)
      - 1949-1961 (Box 431)
      - 1962-1969 (Box 432)
    - Provost's Office, 1965-1968 (Box 432)
    - Radiological safety, 1958-1964 (Box 432)
    - Rebstock Hall renovations, 1960-1967, (2 folders) (Box 432)
    - Registrar, 1966-1968 (Box 432)
    - Research assistants, 1949-1963, (2 folders) (Box 432)
    - Research assistants, 1949-1963, (4 folders) (Box 433)
    - School of Engineering and Applied Science, 1967-1969 (Box 433)
    - Seminars, 1949-1952, (2 folders) (Box 433)
    - Senate Council Budget Committee, 1959, (3 folders) (Box 434)
    - Speeches and Writings (Box 434)
      - 1952-1964, (4 folders) (Box 434)
      - 1964-1969, (6 folders) (Box 435)
      - 1970-1974, (4 folders) (Box 436)
    - Student advising, 1965-1967, (3 folders) (Box 436)
    - Travel (Box 437)
      - 1950-1959, (7 folders) (Box 437)
      - 1960-1964, (4 folders) (Box 438)
    - Undergraduate botany courses (Box 438)
      - 1950-1965, (3 folders) (Box 438)
      - 1966-1969, (6 folders) (Box 439)
      - 1966-1969, (3 folders) (Box 440)
    - University Senate, 1965-1969, (2 folders) (Box 440)
    - Vietnam War, 1966-1969 (Box 440)
    - Wilson, Linda S., 1969-1975, (2 folders) (Box 441)
    - Work-study students, 1966-1969 (Box 441)
    - Zucker, Milton, 1949-1960 (Box 441)
- 1990 Addition, 1943-1979 (Box 442-491)
  The 1990 Addition is arranged into seven subseries: General Correspondence, Speeches and Writings, Subject File, Research File, Photographs and Slides, Miscellany and Oversize.
  - General Correspondence, 1956-1979 (Box 442-443)
    Correspondence
    Arranged chronologically.
    - 1956-1970, (7 folders) (Box 442)
    - 1970-1979, undated, (5 folders) (Box 443)
  - Speeches and Writings File, 1943-1979 (Box 443-452)
    Articles and papers, a book file, speeches and related printed material, and an untitled manuscript.
    Arranged alphabetically by type of material.
    - Programs and advertisements (Box 443)
      - 1957-1969, (2 folders) (Box 443)
      - 1970-1976, undated, (2 folders) (Box 444)
    - Speeches, 1956-1978, undated, (5 folders) (Box 444)
    - Writings (Box 445)
      - By Commoner (Box 445)
        - Correspondence (Box 445)
          - General, 1954-1975, (2 folders) (Box 445)
          - Technology of Profit, Russian translation, 1975-1977 (Box 445)
        - Articles and papers (Box 445)
          - 1943-1963, (6 folders) (Box 445)
          - 1964-1971, (6 folders) (Box 446)
          - 1971-1973, (5 folders) (Box 447)
          - 1973-1979, undated, (7 folders) (Box 448)
        - Books (Box 449)
          - Foreign translations, (2 folders) (Box 449)
          - Foreign translations, (2 folders) (Box 450)
          - Science and Survival, summary by population census, 1967 (Box 451)
          - Untitled manuscript, (5 folders) (Box 451)
          - Untitled manuscript, (2 folders) (Box 452)
        - Reviews of articles and reports, 1950, 1965 (Box 452)
      - By others, 1970, undated (Box 452)
      - Unidentified, 1957, undated (Box 452)
  - Subject File, 1948-1978 (Box 452-466)
    The Subject file includes material on a variety of scientic and environmental topics, as well as other topics such as patents, travel, grant applications, and files on organizations such as the American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) and the Center for the Biology of Natural Systems (CBNS).
    Material types include correspondence, printed matter, committee papers, and other miscellaneous papers.
    Arranged alphabetically by topic or name of individual or organization.
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 452)
      - Committee on Science, integrity of science, 1962-1964, (2 folders) (Box 452)
      - General, 1963-1973 (Box 453)
      - Symposium, 1971 (Box 453)
      - Youth Council, 1971 (Box 453)
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1966-1967 (Box 453)
    - Auto emission standards, 1972-1973, (2 folders) (Box 453)
    - Auto emission standards, 1972-1973, (3 folders) (Box 454)
    - Biographical file, 1950-1970, (3 folders) (Box 454)
    - Botany (Box 454)
      - Botany Department, 1968-1969 (Box 454)
      - Course no. 104, 1969 (Box 455)
      - Seminar, 1960 (Box 455)
    - Center for the Biology of Natural Systems (Box 455)
      - Botany building, 1967, (3 folders) (Box 455)
      - Environmental library, 1974-1976 (Box 455)
    - Comité de Cooperación Comunal Humanitaria, 1964-1967 (Box 456)
    - "C" miscellaneous, 1968-1970 (Box 456)
    - DNA, 1968-1971, undated (Box 456)
    - Edison Foundation Institute, 1960-1961 (Box 456)
    - Environmental Agenda Development Committee and Advisory, 1976 (Box 456)